<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Nick Burns</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.nick.burns.io/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.nick.burns.io/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nick.burns.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2023-04-19T08:35:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Nick Burns</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>makita bit holders</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.nick.burns.io/2023/04/19/makita-bit-holders.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.nick.burns.io/2023/04/19/makita-bit-holders.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-19T08:35:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-23T00:14:39-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Burns</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As someone who does a lot of DIY work around the house, I found that my drill bits were constantly getting lost or misplaced. I needed a way to keep them organized and easily accessible. I wanted something that would help me avoid stuffing a handful...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As someone who does a lot of DIY work around the house, I found that my drill bits were constantly getting lost or misplaced. I needed a way to keep them organized and easily accessible. I wanted something that would help me avoid stuffing a handful of them in my pocket to fumble through, or leaving them lying out to get lost. After seeing the price of commercially available ones I thought I could design something similar and print it on my 3D printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by sketching out some ideas on paper, and making note of the dimensions of the bit shanks and magnets, I then moved on to designing the holder using CAD software. I wanted to make sure that the holder would fit enough of my drill bits and be sturdy enough. &lt;a href="/2023/04/19/makita-bit-holders/bit-holder.stl"&gt;Download the STL here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type="module" src="https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/model-viewer/3.0.1/model-viewer.min.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;model-viewer id="makita-bit-holder" src="/2023/04/19/makita-bit-holders/bit-holder.glb" environment-image="legacy" auto-rotate="" interaction-prompt="none" shadow-intensity="1" camera-controls=""&gt;
&lt;/model-viewer&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the design finalized, I exported the file and sent it to my 3D printer. I used a nice blue PLA filament, and printed it vertically so it wouldn't need supports (although it makes it less strong). I'll reassess if I manage to break it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short print, my holder was complete. I was thrilled with how it turned out. The holder is compact and mounts to the extra hook mount on my drill and driver. The holes were a bit tight, so I chucked one in backwards and used it to ream the holes out before pressing in the magnets with my bench vise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/2023/04/19/makita-bit-holders/finished.jpg" alt="finished holder on drill" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
